Usha Bommasamudram

Software Engineer

O Edison, NJ, 08820

732-646-0441

usha.bpr@gmail.com

Energetic and decisive team member, able to assess and implement sophisticated technologies while championing business process improvement. Over 8 years of experience in C++ & VC++ application development and maintenance. Strengths include attention to detail, perseverance, ability to learn, and work on new technologies.



Skills

Languages :C, C++,VC++, Java (Basic), SQL, PL/SQL, VB, C#.Net.

Database : Oracle 8i/9i.

Tools: Lead Tools, Installshield, VISE Installer.

OS: Windows 95/98/2K/XP/7, MAC OS9/OSX.

SCMTools:Rational Clear Case, Source offsite, perforce,CQ



Work History

Lead Engineer

GE Transportation, Bangalore, India

Information-Based Solutions Controller Simulator/Tools

- Developed new applications and simulators using VC++, MFC.
- Developed simulators for Expert on Alert (EOA), Trip Optimizer(TO) which
 communicates through the serial port, Ethernet, data is in different formats
 HEX, ASCII. The simulators developed helped shorten development time, by
 reducing dependency on hardware controllers, overall resulting in cost
 saving.
- Implemented customized protocols and standard protocols, which were used by the development team, system team, and customers.
- Enhancements implementation and defect resolution to WIn32, C++ applications.
- High-Level and Detailed Design document creation.
- Test case design and execution.
- Performance testing of the product LOCOCOMM to check CPU and memory usage of each application.
- Trained new team members and contractors.

2008-08 - 2012-05

2007-08 - 2008-08

Project Engineer

GE Transportation, Bangalore, India

Information-Based Solutions LOCOCOMM

- Developed new applications and simulators in VC++, Win32 to recreate the situations of the Locomotive.
- Application enhancements and defect resolution running on the LOCOCOMM.
- High-Level and Detailed Design document creation.
- Test case design and execution.
- Performed remote monitoring and diagnostic operations (RMD) for locomotive applications on the Communication management unit (CMU).
- Developed multiple simulators for testing the applications before testing on the field, resulting in faster deployment of products.

2005-11 - 2007-08

Senior Software Engineer

Wipro Technologies, Bangalore, India

CPS, Hewlett-Packard

- Developed new printer applications in VC++, MFC, and Win32.
- Customized printer applications for multiple locales and unit tested.
- Built and released printer drivers and applications using the install shield for both Windows and Mac OS.
- Enhancements implementation and defect resolution to printer applications of Windows and Mac OS.
- High-Level and Detailed Design document creation.
- Test case design and execution for components of printers and applications.
- Trained the new team members.

2004-02 - 2005-11

Software Engineer

Wipro Technologies, Bangalore, India

OPG, Hewlett-Packard

- Developed new printer applications in VC++, MFC, and Win32 to display, edit, and print images.
- Developed and modified applications using the LEAD tools to accommodate advanced image editing operations, printing the images through the serial and parallel port.
- Customized printer applications for multiple locales and unit tested.
- Enhancements implementation and defect resolution to printer applications.
- High-Level and Detailed Design document creation.
- Test case design and execution for components of printers and applications.
- Trained the contractors.



Education

1999-07 - 2003-04

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science And Information Technology

Srinivasa Institute Of Technology - Management Studies, Chittoor, AP, India.